CONTACT

+6010-3963927



🔼 zakirahsharifuddin@gmail.com



Selama, Perak.

🔘 zakirahsharifuddin

ZAKIRAH BINTI SHARIFUDDIN

Software Engineer



SOFT SKILLS

Active Listening Teamwork

Presentation & Public Speaking

Written & Oral Communication

Creativity & Problem Solving

ABOUT ME

Seeking for a Software Engineer position where I can use my programming skills and experience to design and develop a software support and solution, applying my four years of computer science studies. I am eager to learn new things to challenge myself.

QUALIFICATION

S.M. Sains Raja Tun Azlan Shah (SERATAS), Taiping (2013-2017)

Engineering science stream

• SPM | 4A+ 4A 2B+

Universiti Teknologi MARA (UiTM), Dengkil

(2018-2019)

(2019-2023)

Foundation of Engineering, CGPA | 3.89

Universiti Sains Malaysia (USM), Penang

Bachelor of Computer Science (Honours), CGPA | 3.40

· Major in Software Engineering

• Minor in Management

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming:

C++, C, Java, Python, PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL, Arduino UNO

Graphic:

AutoCAD, Adobe Photoshop

Platform:

Windows & LINUX operating system, Microsoft Office, Android Studio, Oracle APEX, PhpMyAdmin, GitHub

Other.

Basic Software, Web and Android Application Development, React Framework

EXPERIENCE

Computer Science Intern: First Solar(M) | Mar - Sept 2022

• Automate data collection for daily report in Integration team and develop a dashboard to facilitate and gather all data, and turn into packages and emails for daily meeting.

Teaching Assistant | Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

• Provides support and assistance to individual students and small groups to help them better understand the content and help them to complete assignments and tutorials.

Freelance Full-Stack Developer | 2022 - Current

• Develop a "Pest Control" website for a small start up company based in Selama, Perak.

REFERENCE

Dr. Azleena Mohd Kassim | USM (Academic Advisor)

Email | azleena.mk@usm.my **Phone** | +604-6533645

Dr. Nor Athiyah Abdullah | USM (Final-Year Project Supervisor)

Email | athiyah@usm.my Phone | +604-6534644

Mr. Gemenis Wong | First Solar(M) (Internship Supervisor)

Email | gwong@firstsolar.com **Phone** | +6017-4718798

PROJECT BASED LEARNING

Journal Studio | Nov 2020 (GitHub)

• Develop a website that can store notes in the database by using HTML, PHP, CSS. and SQL.

USM Finder Kit | Jan 2021 (GitHub)

• Developing and android application using Android Studio in Java.

JomShare | Sept 2021 - Present (GitHub)

• Innovation project for sustainability by creating a surplus food website using location based.

MyEventOrg: Final-Year Project | Oct 2022 (GitHub)

• Develop a system and dashboard to manage souvenirs for event held in School of Computer Science, USM, and can act as ecommerce platform to handle all booking, buying and selling merchandises.